This is the first of what will be a considerable sequence of videos on bottom
这是底部相当多的视频序列中的第一个
up parsing. The first thing to know is that bottom up parsing is more general
向上解析。首先要知道的是，自下而上解析更通用。
than deterministic top down parsing. So recall we talked about recursive descent,
而不是确定性的自上而下解析。回想一下，我们谈过递归下降，
which is a completely general parsing algorithm, but requires backtracking. And
这是一个完全通用的解析算法，但需要回溯。和
now we're focused on deterministic techniques and we talked about L-L one or
现在我们把重点放在确定性技术上，我们谈到了L-L One或
predictive parsing last time. And now we're gonna switch, shift gears and talk
上次的预测分析。现在我们要交换意见，换换话题，谈谈
about bottom up parsing. And it turns out though even the bottom up parsing is more
关于自下而上的解析。事实证明，即使是自下而上的解析也要
general, it's just as efficient, and it uses all of the ideas that we learned in
总而言之，它是同样高效的，它使用了我们在中学到的所有想法
top down parsing. And in fact, bottom up. Parsing is the preferred method that's
自上而下解析。事实上，是自下而上的。解析是首选的方法，因为
using most of the parser generator tools. So, one good thing about bottom up
使用大多数解析器生成器工具。所以，自下而上有一个好处
parcers, is they don't need left factored grammars, so we can revert to the natural
Parcers，是他们不需要左因式语法，所以我们可以恢复到自然
grammar for our example and natural here is in quotes, because we still have to
我们示例的语法和这里的自然语法用引号括起来，因为我们仍然需要
encode the precedence of plus and times, so bottom up parcers aren't going to deal
对加号和倍数的优先级进行编码，这样自下而上的地块就不会处理
with ambiguous grammars. And let's just as an example, consider how a bottom up
语法模棱两可。让我们举个例子，考虑一下自下而上的
parcer would work on the following, typical input string. So the first thing
PARCER将处理以下典型的输入字符串。所以第一件事就是
to know about bottom up parsing is that it reduces, what we call reduces a string
要知道自下而上的解析是减少的，我们称之为减少字符串
into the start symbol by inverting productions, by running productions
通过反转乘积，通过运行乘积添加到开始符号中
backwards. So here's an example. On the left hand side is the sequence of states
往后倒。这里有一个例子。左侧是状态序列
of the string. On the right hand side are the productions that were used And the
这根线的一部分。右手边是使用过的产品和
thing to observe, let's just look at the very first step. Is that we began with the
要观察的东西，让我们只看第一步。我们是从
entire string. We began with the, the, the string of terminals. And we picked some of
整个字符串。我们从终端的这个，那个，那串开始。我们挑选了一些
those terminals. In this case, just one, this particular Int right here. And we ran
那些终端。在这种情况下，只有一个，这个特定的Int就在这里。然后我们就跑了
a production backwards. We replaced the Int here by the left side of the
一部倒排的作品。我们将这里的Int替换为
production. We began with, we matched the right side of the production Int and we
制作。我们首先，我们匹配了生产Int的右侧，我们
replaced it by the left side. So Int went backwards here to T. And then in the next
已将其更换为左侧。所以Int在这里倒退到T，然后在下一个
step, we took Int times T, this substr ing of The, string that we're working on And
一步，我们取Int乘以T，这是我们正在处理的字符串的减字符串，
we replace it by the left-hand side of this production. N times T was replaced by
我们把它换成这部作品的左手边。N乘以T替换为
T, and so on. At each step here, we're matching some portion of the string. And
T，以此类推。在这里的每一步，我们都在匹配字符串的某一部分。和
I'm underlining the portion that's being replaced at each step. And we're running,
我在每一步都要替换的部分下划线。我们在奔跑，
and that matches the right hand side of sum production. And then we're replacing
这与SUM乘积的右边相匹配。然后我们要替换掉
that substring by the left hand side. And finally, this entire, string here is
左手边的那个子串。最后，这里的整个字符串是
replaced by E. And we wind up at the start symbol. So we began with an input string.
替换为E，我们在开始符号处结束。所以我们从一个输入字符串开始。
This is our input string up here. Alright put string of tokens and we end with the
这是我们的输入字符串。好的，放上一串代币，我们以
start symbol down here And if you read the moves in this direction If you start at
从这里开始符号，如果你读到了这个方向的动作，如果你从
the bottom and read towards the top. Well, these are just productions. And in fact
从底部往下看，往上看。嗯，这些只是作品。事实上，
this whole thing is a derivation. This is just a normal derivation going from bottom
这整件事都是衍生出来的。这只是一个从下往下的正常推导
to top. But in this direction when we run it backwards beginning with the string
到顶端。但是在这个方向上，当我们从字符串开始向后运行时
towards the start symbol, we call these reductions. And I haven't told you exactly
对于开始符号，我们称这些减量为。我还没有确切地告诉你
how we decided what reductions to do, and you might wonder, well, how I knew to do
我们是如何决定要做什么减税的，你可能会想，嗯，我是怎么知道要这么做的？
this particular sequence of reductions. Well, here's another interesting property
这种特殊的减少顺序。嗯，这是另一个有趣的地方
of bottom-up parsing. So, if you read the productions backwards, they trace a
自下而上的解析。所以，如果你倒着读这些结果，它们会追溯到一个
rightmost derivation, so if we begin here with e, so we're gonna--so remember the
最右边的派生，所以如果我们从e开始，那么我们要--所以记住
parser is actually going in this direction, so this is the direction of
解析器实际上正朝着这个方向前进，所以这就是
parsing here. But now we're gonna look at the steps the parser took in reverse, and
在这里解析。但现在我们要看看解析器反向执行的步骤，
we're going to see that it was, in fact, a rightmost derivation. So here, E went to
我们将看到，事实上，这是一个最右边的派生。所以在这里，E去了
T+E. Well, E was the only non terminal. But then E here is the one that's
T+E。嗯，E是唯一的非末端。但这里的E才是
expanded, it's the rightmost non terminal. And then this T is expanded, it's also the
扩展后，它是最右边的非终结点。然后这个T被扩展，它也是
rightmost non terminal to get int. And now this T is the rightmost tom-, non
要获取int的最右边的非终结符。现在这个T是最右边的汤姆-，不
terminal. It's expanded to get Int times T. And then this is the only end right
终点站。它被扩展为Int乘以T，然后这是唯一正确的结束
most non terminal, and so we wind up with the whole input string, Int times Int plus
大多数都不是终结符，所以我们最终得到了整个输入字符串，Int乘以Int+
int. And this leads us to The first important f act about bottom up parsing,
内部这就把我们带到了关于自下而上解析的第一个重要环节，
which is that a bottom up parser traces a rightmost derivation in reverse, all
即自下而上的解析器以相反的方式跟踪最右边的派生，所有
right? So if you're ever having trouble with bottom up parsing, it's always
对吗？因此，如果您在自下而上解析时遇到问题，它总是
helpful to go back to this basic fact. Bottom up parser traces a rightmost
回到这个基本事实是有帮助的。自下而上的解析器跟踪最右边的
derivation, but it does so in reverse by using reductions instead of productions.
派生，但它通过使用减法而不是乘积进行相反的操作。
So here's the series of reductions again. Shown on the left And here is the parse
所以这又是一系列的减少。如左边所示，这里是解析
tree, that is constructed, from those reductions. And this is actually I think,
这棵树，就是从这些减量中构造出来的。这实际上是我认为的，
a very helpful picture, if we animate it, to see the sequence of steps, and to see
这是一幅非常有帮助的图片，如果我们将其动画化，以查看步骤的顺序，并查看
what a bottom up parser is really doing. So here we begin with the input string.
自下而上的解析器到底在做什么。所以这里我们从输入字符串开始。
Over here And we show the same input string here. And now we're just going to
在这里，我们在这里显示相同的输入字符串。现在我们要做的就是
walk through the sequence of steps that the, bottom up parser takes A series of
演练自下而上解析器执行的一系列步骤
reductions. And show how it builds an entire parse tree. And the basic idea is
减价。并展示它是如何构建整个解析树的。它的基本思想是
that in each step we're performing a reduction. And remember when we do a
在每一步中我们都在进行减量。记住当我们做一个
reduction we replace the children of the right hand side of sum production by its
减法将和乘积右侧的子代替换为
left hand side. And just like when we were doing top down parson well, we will do the
左手边。就像我们做自上而下的牧师一样，我们会做
same thing here. In the input, and then we make T its parent. And now you can see
这里也是一样。在输入中，然后我们将T设为它的父级。现在你可以看到
what's going to happen. A top down parser begins with the start symbol, and produces
接下来会发生什么。自上而下的解析器以开始符号开始，并生成
the tree incrementally by expanding some non terminal, at the frontier. At the
这棵树在边界通过扩展一些非末端递增。在
current, at a current leaf of the partially constructed parse tree. The
当前，在部分构造的解析树的当前叶。这个
bottom up parsers is going to begin with all the leaves of the eventual pars tree
自下而上的解析器将从最终解析树的所有叶子开始
The entire input. And it's going to build little trees on top of those. And it's
整个输入。它将在这些树的上面建造一些小树。而且它是
going to be pasting together all the sub-trees that it's put together so far to
把到目前为止放在一起的所有子树粘贴在一起
build the complete tree. Let's walk a few more steps and see how that happens. So in
构建完整的树。让我们再走几步，看看会发生什么。所以在
the next step, we go from Int times T to T, so Int times and the sub tree rooted at
下一步，我们从Int乘T到T，所以Int乘以子树为根
the other T, become children of this non terminal T and you can see we've taken
另一个T，成为这个非终端T的子节点，你可以看到我们已经
these three sub trees here, and pasted them together into a larger tree. So as we
这三棵子树放在这里，然后把它们贴在一起，做成一棵更大的树。所以当我们
go throug h the parcer, bigger and bigger portions of the original input are gonna
通过寄存处，原始输入的越来越大的部分将
be pasted together into larger and larger trees. And the next reduction takes the
被贴在一起，变成越来越大的树。而下一次降价则需要
Int to the far into the input, and reduces it to T. And that gets reduced to E, and
INT到远端的输入，并将其缩减为T，它将被缩减为E，并且
then. At the very end the three remaining sub trees are all pasted together into one
然后。最后，剩下的三棵子树全部粘贴在一起
parse tree for the whole thing with a start symbol as the root.
以开始符号为根，解析整个对象的解析树。